A Guide to the Virginia. Bureau of Vital Statistics. West Virginia Vital Statistics, 1853-1863
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia. Bureau of Vital Statistics. West Virginia Vital Statistics, 1853-1863
The Library of Virginia
38788
42 cu. ft. (28 boxes)
Virginia. Bureau of Vital Statistics.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Virginia Dept. of Health.
Biographical Information
The state of West Virginia was formed on 13 May 1862 and consisted of the following fifty counties that were formerly in Virginia: Barbour, Berkeley, Boone, Braxton, Brooke, Cabell, Calhoun, Clay, Doddridge, Fayette, Gilmer, Greenbrier, Hampshire, Hancock, Hardy, Harrison, Jackson, Jefferson, Kanawha, Lewis, Logan, Marion, Marshall, Marion, McDowell, Mercer, Monongalia, Monroe, Morgan, Nicholas, Ohio, Pendleton, Pleasants, Pocahontas, Preston, Putnam, Raleigh, Randolph, Ritchie, Roane, Taylor, Tucker, Tyler, Upshur, Wayne, Webster, Wetzel, Wirt, Wood and Wyoming.
Scope and Content
Contains registers of births, deaths and marriages of counties in Virginia that were later incorporated into West Virginia in 1863. Birth Registers include: date of birth, name, color, and sex of the child, place of birth, father's name, occupation and residence, name of mother, any deformities or circumstances of interest, and the source of the information. Death registers include: full name, race, and sex of the deceased, date, place and cause of death, name of parents, birthdate and occupation of the deceased, name of the coroner and the source of the information. Marriage registers include: date and place of the marriage, full names of husband and wife, age and condition, place of their births, place of residence, names of their parents, occupations, and the name of the person performing the ceremony.
Unfortunately, most of these records are incomplete with gaps in coverage from county to county. In particular, please note that the birth registers for McDowell County are absent from the collection. Also please note that the original materials are in poor condition. Please use microfilm. Note that the microfilm was made from poor originals and that the best possible image has been achieved considering the condition of the original materials.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by county name.
Contents List
- Barbour - Berkeley Counties, 1853-1863 (Box 1)
- Boone - Brooke Counties, 1853-1863 (Box 2)
- Cabell - Doddridge Counties, 1853-1863 (Box 3)
- Fayette - Gilmer Counties, 1853-1863 (Box 4)
- Greenbrier County, 1853-1863 (Box 5)
- Hampshire - Hancock Counties, 1853-1863 (Box 6)
- Hardy County, 1853-1863 (Box 7)
- Harrison County, 1853-1863 (Box 8)
- Jackson County, 1853-1863 (Box 9)
- Jefferson County, 1853-1863 (Box 10)
- Kanawha County, 1853-1863 (Box 11)
- Lewis - Logan Counties, 1853-1863 (Box 12)
- Marion County, 1853-1863 (Box 13)
- Marshall - Mason Counties, 1853-1863 (Box 14)
- McDowell - Mercer Counties, 1853-1863 (Box 15)
- Monongalia County, 1853-1863 (Box 16)
- Monroe - Nicholas Counties, 1853-1863 (Box 17)
- Ohio County, 1853-1863 (Box 18)
- Pendleton - Pocahontas Counties, 1853-1863 (Box 19)
- Preston County, 1853-1863 (Box 20)
- Putnam - Raleigh Counties, 1853-1863 (Box 21)
- Randolph - Ritchie Counties, 1853-1863 (Box 22)
- Roane - Taylor Counties, 1853-1863 (Box 23)
- Tucker - Tyler Counties, 1853-1863 (Box 24)
- Upshur - Webster Counties, 1853-1863 (Box 25)
- Wetzel - Wirt Counties, 1853-1863 (Box 26)
- Wood - Wyoming Counties, 1853-1863 (Box 27)
- Fragments, 1853-1863 (Box 28)